(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-29T02:29:07.635271",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
お待たせしました！！ 今日はいっぱい楽しんでいってね！！
Thanks for waiting! Hope you enjoy yourselves today!
いっせーのせ で 君とだけ！
On the count of three, with just you!
もう少し 眠りたいけど
I want to sleep just a little more,
もったいないよ
but it'd be such a waste,
今日は sunday
today is Sunday!
楽しいこと やりたいこと
All the fun things, all the things I want to do—
wake up ! 始めようよ
Wake up! Let's get started.
めくりめく季節 君と次のステージへ
Through the revolving seasons, to the next stage with you!
声を合わせ 扉開けて 駆け出せ 迷わずに
Voices blending, doors opening, running forth without hesitation!
転んでも かっこ悪くても イイじゃない
Stumbling or looking uncool is totally fine!
stand up ! イメージもっと 重ねて行く その先で
Stand up! Layering our images higher and higher, beyond that point...
いっせーのせ で 君とだけ！
On the count of three, with just you!
ハイタッチ 手たたいて 奏でる メロディを
High-five, clapping our hands to play this melody,
合図に走り出せ go ! 君となら 怖くない
Running out on cue—go! With you, I'm not afraid.
ハイタッチ 手と手 たたいて 重ねる そのメモリーは
High-five, hand in hand, clapping to stack up those memories,
明日へのエネルギー yeah ! さあ行こうよ もっと先へ 君となら happy lucky life !
Energy for tomorrow, yeah! Let's go further ahead, with you it's a happy lucky life!
あの日 夢の続き 追い付く その日まで
Until the day we catch up to the continuation of the dream we saw that day,
涙なんて 振り切るくらい もっと スピードアップ
Speeding up even more to shake off any tears,
どんな未来になっても 後悔しないよ 自分自身で選んだ道 踏み出せ 迷わずに
No matter what future awaits, I won't regret it—stepping forth on the path I chose myself without hesitation!
落ち込んで 進めなくなった時は
When I'm feeling down and can't move forward,
wake up ! 思い返す 夢見た頃の記憶を 手と手で奏でる 叶える 煌めきを 君とだけ！
Wake up! Remembering the memories of when I dreamed, playing the sparkling dreams we make true, with just you!
ハイタッチ その度に 繋がっている 心 一人じゃないことを そう気付かせてくれたよね
High-five, every time our hearts connect, reminding me that I'm not alone.
ハイタッチ その度に繋がっていく心
High touch, with every touch, our hearts connect,
一人じゃないことをそう気付かせてくれたよね
you made me realize I'm not alone.
ハイタッチ 手と手 叩いて 奏でる そのメロディーが
High touch, clapping hands, playing that melody
世界に届くまで この夢は続いてく
until it reaches the world, this dream will go on.
君とならハッピーラッキーライフ！
With you, it's a happy lucky life!
シブヤ！このライブに来てくれてありがとー！
Shibuya! Thank you for coming to this live!
今日はいっぱい楽しんでいってな！
Have a lot of fun today!
みんな盛り上がっていこー！
Let's get hyped everyone!
くじいて歩けない日は おんぶしてあげる君を
On days when you're discouraged and can't walk, I'll carry you on my back.
ほら見てそっちの方が強く地面踏み込める
Look, that way you can stomp the ground even harder.
巡り巡る日々を 辿り夢見たステージへ
Following the spinning days to the stage we dreamed of,
届くそんな日を見つめて 起こそう君とだけ
gazing at that day when it reaches, let's create it, just you and me.
手と手を鳴らすたび 小さなビッグバン
Every time we clap our hands, a small Big Bang
無限のそのチカラを受け取って進め！
receive that infinite power and push forward!
ハイタッチ 手と手 叩いて 奏でる メロディーを
High touch, clapping hands, playing the melody
合図に走り出せ 君となら怖くない
run at the signal, with you I'm not afraid.
ハイタッチ 手と手 叩いて 重ねる そのメモリーは
High touch, clapping hands, overlapping memories
明日へのエネルギー さあ行こうよもっと先へ 君とならハッピーラッキーライフ！
energy for tomorrow, let's go further ahead, with you it's a happy lucky life!
夜に浮かんでいた
Floating in the night,
海月のような月が爆ぜた
a moon like a jellyfish burst open.
バス停の背を覗えば あの夏の君が頭にいる
Peeking behind the bus stop, that summer's you is in my head.
だけ
That's all.
鳥居 乾いた雲 夏の匂いが頬を撫でる
Torii gates, dry clouds, the scent of summer caresses my cheeks.
大人になるまでほら 背伸びしたままで
Standing on tiptoes until I grow up.
遊び疲れたら バス停裏で空でも見よう
When tired of playing, let's look at the sky behind the bus stop.
じかに夏が暮れても きっときっと覚えてるから
Even if summer fades away close by, I'm sure, I'm sure I'll remember.
追い付けないまま 大人になって
Without ever catching up, growing up,
君のポケットに夜が咲く
night blooms in your pocket.
口に出せないなら 僕は一人だ
If I can't put it into words, I'm alone.
それでいいから もう諦めてる
That's fine, I've already given up.
だけ
That's all.
夏日 乾いた雲 山桜桃梅 錆びた標識
Summer days, dry clouds, cherry trees, a rusted sign,
記憶の中は いつも夏の匂いがする
the scent of summer is always in my memories.
写真なんて紙切れだ 想い出なんてただのゴミだ
A photograph is just a scrap of paper, memories are nothing but trash.
それがわからないから 口を噤んだまま
I didn't understand that, so I kept my mouth shut.
絶えず君のいこふ 記憶に夏野の石一つ
In my memory there is a single summer stone where you constantly rest.
俯いたまま 大人になって
Growing up with my head hanging down,
追いつけない ただ君に晴れ
never catching up, just a sunny day for you.
口に出せないまま 坂を上った
Without ever being able to put it into words, I climbed the hill.
僕らの影に 夜が咲いていく
And our shadows bloomed in the night.
俯いたまま 大人になって
Growing up with my head hanging down,
君が思うまま 手を叩け
so just clap your hands as you like.
陽の落ちる坂道を上って
Climbing the hill as the sun goes down,
僕らの影は 追いつけないまま
our shadows, never catching up...
追いかけられないまま大人になって
Growing up without ever catching up,
君のポケットに夜が咲く
night blooms in your pocket.
口に出せないなら僕は一人だ
If I can't put it into words, I'll be alone,
それでいいだろうもう諦めてる
so that's fine, I've already given up.
君の思い出を噛み締めてる
I'm just chewing on the memory of you.
みんなお待たせいたしました！
Everyone, thank you for waiting!
ということでね！始まりました！
So, yeah! It has started!
大空スバル3周年記念ライブお待たせいたしました！
Oozora Subaru's 3rd Anniversary Live! Thank you for waiting!
ということでですね、みんな今日はもうどんどん盛り上がっていきたいと思います！
So today, everyone, we're going to get more and more hyped up!
おもうんですけれども、もう早速ねちょっと時間もないから次の曲に行ってみようかなって思いたいんですけど！
Even though I say that, we don't have much time, so I'd like to move on to the next song!
なんとここで！みんなには練習してもらうことがあります！
And here, everyone has something I want you to practice!
それではこの子と一緒に練習しよう！
So let's practice together with this kid!
どうぞ！ビデオスタート！
Go ahead! Video start!
こんにちは、カバーの取締役の谷郷元昭です。
Hello, I'm Motoaki Tanigo, CEO of Cover.
大空スバル3周年記念ライブにお越しいただきありがとうございます。
Thank you for attending Oozora Subaru's 3rd Anniversary Live.
これから大空スバルアイドルタイムになりますので、皆さんと一緒に掛け声の練習をしたいと思います。
From now on, it will be Oozora Subaru's idol time, so I'd like everyone to practice cheering together.
皆さんももっともっとコメントで打ってください。
Everyone, please type more and more in the comments.
好きになって、もっと！まだまだ足りないぞ。
Become fond of me, more! Still not enough.
もう一回いきます。好きになって、もっと！
Let's go once more. Become fond of me, more!
なんてそのポーズ？
What's with that pose?
ポーズを見て。好きになって、もっと！
Look at the pose. Become fond of me, more!
なんてそのポーズ？完璧に乗って、完璧に続けて聞いてください。
What's with that pose? Ride it perfectly, and continue listening perfectly.
大空スバルで「ファンサ」、そして初オリジナル曲「太陽少女」です。
Oozora Subaru with 'Fansha', and her first original song 'Taiyou Shoujo'.
太陽少女でみんな！突然でできてびっくりしちゃったんじゃないかな？
Taiyou Shoujo, everyone! Weren't you surprised by it coming out so suddenly?
スバルも結構、ちょっといろんな汗かいちゃった！
Subaru worked up quite a sweat!
ですけどね、本当にね、野郎ありがとう！
But really, guys, thank you!
ちなみに、野郎の言った通り、ここからは2曲続けてやりたいと思いますので！
By the way, as the guys said, from here on we want to do two songs in a row!
スバルもね、気持ちを落ち着けて、それでは、やりたいと思います！
Subaru will calm down her feelings too. So, we'd like to do it!
2曲続けて聴いてください！ファンサ、太陽少女！
Please listen to two songs in a row! Fansha and Taiyou Shoujo!
好きになって！もっと！
Become fond of me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもった投げキスで”
Repaying you with "a loving flying kiss"
気のせいじゃない 目は合ってるよ
It's not my imagination, our eyes are meeting.
ハート作って 恋しちゃって下さい！
Make a heart and fall in love, please!
やれること 何でもします
I'll do whatever can be done.
NG無しで 体当たり挑戦
Body-slamming challenges with zero NGs.
エゴサで見つけたアンチのコメ ふざけんな誰より分かってるし
Haters' comments found via ego-surfing—don't bullshit me, I understand better than anyone.
でも大丈夫 ステージに立てばみんながいる
But it's okay, if I stand on stage, everyone is here.
好きになって！もっと！
Become fond of me! More!
私を見て！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもった投げキスで”
Repaying you with "a loving flying kiss"
虜にする！もっと！
Captivating you! More!
夢を見せる！もっと！
Showing you dreams! More!
楽しんでって 愛のこもったスペシャルナイト ファンサしちゃうぞ
Enjoy it, a special night filled with love, I'll give you fan service!
お手紙も書いてください！
Please write letters too!
何度も読んで 宝物ににします
I'll read them many times and make them my treasure.
スキャンダル まだ早いけど
Scandals are still too early, but
裏切りません！ 宣言しときます
I won't betray you! I declare that.
嫉妬嫌がらせには負けない ふざけんな実力で勝ってやる
I won't lose to jealousy and harassment—don't bullshit me, I'll win with pure skill.
だからやめない 負けず嫌い 私はいる
That's why I won't quit, the sore loser I am is here.
こぶし上げて！もっと！
Raise your fists! More!
汗をかいて！もっと！
Sweat! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもったスパビームで”
Repaying you with "a loving spa beam"
大歓声！もっと！
Great cheers! More!
まだまだね！ねぇ？もっと！
Still not enough! Hey? More!
受け止めてね 愛のこもったわがままソング ファンサしちゃうぞ
Receive it, a selfish song filled with love, I'll give you fan service!
近づく 寂しいね
It's getting closer, how lonely...
楽しいのに 泣きそうだよ
Even though it's fun, I feel like crying.
次も 次も また会えるよね
We'll meet again next time, right?
約束！
I promise!
今日は集まってのライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to today's live!
最後まで楽しんでってくれよな！
Enjoy it all the way to the end!
優しさに溢れている言葉も
Even words overflowing with kindness,
心ない誰かの言葉さえも
even the careless words of someone heartless,
必要なんだ 強くなったろう
they're necessary. Have I grown stronger?
好きに叫べ もっと
Shout however you like, more!
楽しんじゃえ もっと
Enjoy yourself, more!
忘れないで
Don't ever forget—
特別な日になりますように
may this become a special day.
共に歌おう ずっと
Let's sing together forever,
共に歩もう ずっと
let's walk together forever.
合言葉は とびきりの L・O・V・E！
Our password is a sparkling L-O-V-E!
L・O・V・E！
L-O-V-E!
好きになって！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More!
私をみて！もっと！
Look at me! More!
恩返しは “愛のこもった投げキスで”
My repayment is with a loving flying kiss!
虜にする！もっと！
Captivating you! More!
夢を見せる！もっと！
Showing you dreams! More!
楽しんでって
Enjoy yourselves,
愛のこもった スペシャルナイト！
a special night filled with love!
ファンサしちゃうぞっ
I'll give you fan service!
キラキラの太陽が ワクワクが待ちきれない
The glittering sun, I can't wait for the excitement!
あれもしたい これもしたい ねぇ Summer time!
I want that, I want this too, hey Summer time!
青い空と白い雲が 心のボルテージ上げていく
The blue sky and white clouds raise the voltage in my heart!
臙脂色のTシャツはね 今年いちばんのレコメンド
My maroon T-shirt is this year's top recommendation!
走り出した海岸線 どこまでだって行けそうだね
The coastline I started running down—it feels like we can go anywhere!
数え切れない 夏休みだね
Countless summer vacations, right?
君も一緒にいこう
Come along with me too!
あっという間に進んでく時計
The clock moves forward in the blink of an eye,
虹が過ぎちゃいない？ マイ・サマータイム！
isn't the rainbow passing us by? My summertime!
全部さいこうのメモリアルにしたい 追い風でみんな連れてって
I want to turn it all into the best memorial, taking everyone with a tailwind!
素晴らしい太陽が 参戦・制服でのジャンプ
The wonderful sun—jumping in our uniforms,
弾ける汗 ほうせきみたいにキラキラ
splashing sweat sparkling like jewels!
眩しく輝き
Shining brightly!
キラキラの太陽が ドキドキがいっぱいです
The glittering sun is full of excitement!
あれもしたい これもしたい ねぇ Summer time!
I want that, I want this too, hey Summer time!
涼しい風 寝転がって 伸び伸び手をおろしてもっと
A cool breeze, lying down, stretching out my hands even more—
夢の中は何だってできちゃう キラキラ光りおとすスパースター
anything is possible in dreams, falling with sparkling light like a superstar!
流れ星を見つけに行こう 夜更かしだってへっちゃらだよ
Let's go find a shooting star, staying up late is no problem at all!
願い事が溢れそうな時は ミルキーウェイ・エンパイアに
When wishes are about to overflow, into the Milky Way Empire—
ちょうどくらいヘトヘトでも平気 みんながくれるファイトがある
Even if we're exhausted, it's fine, we have everyone's fighting spirit!
どこまでだって駆け抜けでゆけるからいいよね
We can run through to the ends of the earth, so that's fine, right?
指をかけ みんな盛り上がってるか！ まだまだ盛り上がっていこう！
Hooking our fingers—are you all hyped up? Let's get even more hyped up!
一つ一つが全部全部が 届いているから上を向いて
Every single thing is reaching you, so look up,
体中に息を吸い込んだなら叫ぶよ
if you've breathed in deep into your body, let out a shout!
みんな大好き！
I love you all so much!
まだまだ盛り上がっていこう！
Let's keep the hype going!
一つ一つが全部全部が 届いているから上を向いて
Every single thing is reaching you, so look up,
体中に息を吸い込んだなら叫ぶよ
if you've breathed in deep into your body, let out a shout!
みんな大好き！
I love you all so much!
毎日が記念日になって 君の心照らすよ
Every day becomes an anniversary, illuminating your heart.
新しい景色を求めるの 驚けじゃうよ 空の果てまで飛んでいこう
Seeking new scenery, I'll surprise you—let's fly to the ends of the sky!
素晴らしい太陽が 参戦・制服でジャンプ！ 弾ける汗 ほうせきみたいにキラキラ
The wonderful sun—jumping in our uniforms, splashing sweat sparkling like jewels!
食わず嫌いはノンノンノン
You can't judge a book by its cover, non-non-non!
我は時代の創成児
I am a child of the times!
これがアヒルの輝き
This is a duck's brilliance!
はーい！ということで！ 太陽少女じゃなくてファンサ！
So! Instead of "Taiyou Shoujo," it's "Fan Service!"
どうだった？どうだった？ かっこよかった？ 聞いたとこびっくりしちゃっしょ！
How was it? How was it? Was it cool? Weren't you surprised when you heard it?
あ、ちょっとね お着替えなんかもしちゃったりして、いい感じにしました。どうだったでしょうか？
Ah, you know, I even changed my outfit and made it look nice. How was it?
もうね本当にね！もう本当にバックダンサーじゃん見たみんな！
Seriously, everyone, look at those back dancers!
あのさ、アヒルじゃん！もう頭がさ、すごいさ、ピカピカしててさ、スバルなんか楽しくなっちゃってよ、うーん！
I mean, look at the ducks! My head was shining so bright, Subaru got all excited, yeah!
ということでですね、ここからはね なんとねまた2曲！ ちょっとね、ちょっとお水飲んでいい？普通に。ごめんなさい！
So, from here on, we have another two songs! Hold on, can I drink some water? Seriously, sorry!
あ、お水こっちだ！ よいしょ、よいしょ。
Ah, the water's over here! Heave-ho, heave-ho.
はーい！ということで、あ、すいません！
Right! So, ah, excuse me!
ということでですね、ちょっとね、あの、ここからまた2曲あるんですよ！で、この2曲ね、なんだと思う？
So, you know, from here we have another two songs! And what do you think these two songs are?
ちょっとなんだと思う？ みんなが好きな曲と、1曲は新曲、歌ったことない曲です。
What do you think? One is a song everyone loves, and the other is a brand new song I've never sung before.
えー！なんだと思う？ってところも楽しみにして、聞いてください！
Eh! Look forward to guessing what it is, and listen up!
それじゃね、このアイドル衣装を着ながら！そうそうね、始めちゃおうかな！
So while wearing this idol outfit! Yeah, I guess I'll get started!
今からもう中盤だからね、もう！もう中盤だけどまだ使えないよな！盛り上がっていくぞ！よーし！
We're already in the middle of the show! Even though it's the middle, we're not done yet! Let's get hyped! Alright!
ということで、じゃあ、始めるか！それではね、じゃあ聞いてください！シンシアリー！
With that, shall we begin? Now then, please listen to this! Sincerely!
知らない言葉を 覚えていくたび
Each time I learn a new, unknown word,
おもかげのなか 手を伸ばすの
I reach out my hand within my memories.
だけどひとりでは
But all alone,
わからない言葉も あるのかもしれない
there may be words I still cannot comprehend.
さよならは苦くて
"Goodbye" is bitter,
アイシテルは遠くにおいがした
while "I love you" carried a distant scent.
たとえようのない
This indescribable
この想いは
feeling
とても怖くて
is so very frightening,
だけどとても愛おしくて わたしなんで泣いてるんだろう
yet so deeply precious—why am I crying?
心になんて答えたらいい?
How should I answer my heart?
言葉はいつでも語るでもなくて
Words are never simply spoken aloud;
わたしはあなたに会いたくなる
they just make me want to see you all the more.
きれいな言葉を覚えていくたび
Each time I learn more beautiful words,
自分のことが嫌いになりそう
I feel like I'm starting to hate myself.
だけど背を向けちゃいけない言葉も
Yet there are words I must not turn my back on—
かなしみは冷たく ありがとうはぬくもりに色づく
sadness is cold, while gratitude is tinged with warmth.
形のないもの触れるたびに あなたの声が胸の奥で響いているの
Each time I touch the intangible, your voice echoes deep within my heart.
書きかけてはやめた
I started writing, but stopped—
あて先のない手紙は
this letter with no addressee
風に揺られる
flutters in the wind,
届けたい人の街まで
seeking the city of the one I want to reach.
始まりの終わりを伝えるために
To convey the end of a beginning,
生きることもをやめないこと
I will never give up on living,
あなたに今日を誇れるように
so I can take pride in today before you.
わたしなんで泣いてるんだろう
Why am I crying?
心になんて答えたらいい?
How should I answer my heart?
言葉はいつでも語るでもなくて
Words are never simply spoken aloud;
わたしはあなたに会いたくなるよ
they just make me want to see you all the more.
書きかけてはやめた
I started writing, but stopped—
あて先のない手紙は 風に揺れる
this letter with no addressee flutters in the wind.
知らない言葉を 覚えていくたび
Each time unknown words come to mind,
おもかげのなか 手を伸ばすの
I reach my hand toward the traces they leave.
だけど一人では 分からない言葉も
But there may be words I can't comprehend alone.
あるのかもしれない
There might be some.
生きること やめないこと
Living my life, never giving up...
あなたに今日 誇れるように
So that I can take pride in today before you.
私なんて 泣いているんだろう
Why am I crying right now?
心になんて 答えられたらいい
How should I answer my heart?
言葉は いつでも 語るでもなくて
Words are never simply spoken,
そこにあるばかり つのるばかり
They're just there, they just keep building up.
私は あなたに 会いたくなるよ
I start wanting to see you.
あたしヴァンパイア
I'm a vampire.
いいの？
Is that okay?
もう無理無理なんて 悪い子ね
It's no use saying "no way," you're a bad kid.
試したいな いっぱい吐いて
I want to try it out, breathing it all out,
まだ絶対いけるよ
I can still definitely go on!
痛い痛い骨 ずっと息継ぎしてる
My aching bones are always catching their breath,
甘くなる不穏の果実
The sweet yet ominous fruit.
飲んでも破天荒しと息をしても
Even if I drink it or breathe wildly,
いらないだけ うるさいだけ
It's just unwanted, just noisy.
誰かといれば それはそれで
If I'm with someone, that in itself
しがみついたって 気持ちには逆らえない
Even if I cling to it, I can't fight my feelings.
離れていても 感じてるエモ
Even when apart, I feel this emotion,
繋がって確かめたら 死ねるかも
If I connect and confirm it, I might just die.
あたしヴァンパイア
I'm a vampire.
もう無理無理なんて 悪い子ね
It's no use saying "no way," you're a bad kid.
試したいな いっぱい吐いて
I want to try it out, breathing it all out,
まだ絶対いけるよ
I can still definitely go on!
好みだって わがままだって
My preferences, my selfishness—
困っちゃうよ なんだかんだ
It's troubling, no matter what.
肝心な点 忘れちゃいけない
You mustn't forget the crucial point,
愛情をください まだ絶対いけるよ
Please give me affection, I can still go on!
内緒の想い あらいざらい
All of my secret feelings, completely—
吐き出したなら まさにばかり
If I spit them all out, it's just right.
割り切れないけど あまりじゃない
I can't accept it, isn't it too much?
そんな朝まで とても
Until such a morning,
繰り返す嫌だ わがままはただ
I hate repeating this, selfishness is just
欲張ってまた チャンスを逃すのだ
Being greedy and letting chances slip away.
悲しいもん 切ないもん
It's sad, it's painful,
君のすべてを 食らうまで
Until I devour your very all.
いいじゃん 楽しいじゃん 気持ちじゃん
Isn't it fine? Isn't it fun? It's all about feeling!
あたしヴァンパイア
I'm a vampire.
もう無理無理なんて 悪い子ね
It's no use saying "no way," you're a bad kid.
試したいな いっぱい吐いて
I want to try it out, breathing it all out,
まだ絶対いけるよ
I can still definitely go on!
もー無理無理なんて そんな君じゃないぜ
Saying "no way" isn't like you at all,
絶賛させてよ
Let me praise you!
好みだって わがままだって
My preferences, my selfishness—
何回でも 星が見えるような輪の中で
Within a ring where stars are visible.
延長をください まだ絶対いけるよ
Please give me an extension, I can still go on!
君もヴァンパイア
You're a vampire too.
あいまずは こっちおいで
First of all, come over here.
絶対いけるよ
I can definitely go on!
はーい！ということで、えーSincerelyとヴァンパイア聞いていただきましたが、どうでしたか？
Hi there! So, you heard Sincerely and Vampire. How was it?
かっこよかった？ ちょっとね、結構ね、フリが激し...
Was it cool? The choreography was pretty intense...
スーパチャ！
Super Chat!
もうちょっとね、バタバタしたんですけどね
It was a bit hectic, but
まあかっこよくね決まってたらいいなと
I hope I looked cool doing it.
思います！はい！
I think! Yes!
ということで、でもね
So, but you know,
えーと、なんだっけ？あ、そうそうそうそうここ
um, what was it? Ah, right right right here,
ここからは今まではスバルは一人だったんだけど
up until now it's just been Subaru alone, but
なんと！ここからはメンバーが会いに来てくれるとのことか！じゃなくて
wha— from here on, members are gonna come see me! No wait—
メンバーがね、会いに来てくれたりすると思うます
I think members might come see me,
でもね、まだね、誰が来るかはねお楽しみなんですよ！まだ言えないんです！
but who's coming is a surprise! I can't say yet!
まぁどんなメンバーがここにやってくるのか、みんなね楽しみしながら待っていてください！はい！
So whatever members come here, everyone please look forward to it and wait! Yes!
はい！で
Yes! And,
スバルはちょっとここで一回お着替えね、もう一度一緒に戻るお着替えをしてこようと思うので、みんなちょっと待っていてください！
Subaru is gonna go change clothes once here, and I'll come back changed together once more, so everyone please wait a bit!
待っててね！待っててね！はい！じゃあスバル行ってくるから、ちょっと待ってて！
Wait for it! Wait for it! Yes! Well Subaru is going, so wait a bit!
お水も飲むんだから！
I gotta drink some water too!
はあ、めちゃ喉渇いた、やべぇ
Phew, my throat's so dry, crap.
よし！ほら！
Alright! Look!
どう？このイカしたサングラスを！
How about this cool sunglasses style?
どう？このイカしたサングラスいかがでしょう
How about these cool sunglasses?
なんとね、今からパーティの気分でね盛り上げていきたいと思います！
And now, I want to get everyone hyped with party vibes!
じゃあそろそろ行こうかな？
Well, shall I get going soon?
それでは、誰が来るかお楽しみに！聞いてください、You & Me
Now then, look forward to who's coming! Please listen to You & Me.
turn it up to the funky beat. that's for you & me
turn it up to the funky beat. 鳴き立てろビート it's only for you & me
Turn it up to the funky beat, strike the beat, it's only for you & me.
瞳にキラキラワンダーランド
A sparkling wonderland in our eyes,
夜空にキスしたバタフライ
a butterfly that kissed the night sky.
おいでエンジェル 一緒にムーンライト
Come on, angel, into the moonlight together,
恋をデコレーション (yeah, yeah)
decorating love (yeah, yeah).
まるでストロベリー 甘いクリームの上に (oh that's sweet)
Like a strawberry on top of sweet cream (oh that's sweet).
only you とっておきのハッピー飾ろう (二人だけの世界)
Only you, let's decorate with special happiness (a world just for two).
いくつもの鍵で キミと扉を開ける (right now)
Opening the door with you using countless keys (right now).
星の (ah) ジュエリー (ah) 降り注ぐ
Starlight (ah) jewelry (ah) raining down,
shining my dream (羽広げてinto your dream)
shining my dream (spreading my wings into your dream).
テトテ メトメ ヒトリト ヒトリ
Hand in hand, eye to eye, one by one,
出会って「ふたり」になる you & me (you & me)
meeting to become "two" — you & me (you & me).
昨日 じゃ ないって それだけで good morning ! (hey) good morning ! (hey)
Just knowing it's not yesterday makes it good morning! (hey) good morning! (hey)
“ハジマリ” でしょ ?
It's a "beginning", right?
ヨル ガ アサ ニ キセツ ガ ハナ ニ 出会って 未来 に なる you & me (with the beat)
Night turns to morning, seasons to flowers, meeting to become the future — you & me (with the beat).
愛 より もっと love な 笑顔 で
With smiles more loving than love itself,
終わん ない happy dance
an endless happy dance.
テトテ メトメ ツマイ 夜空とスカイ
Hand in hand, eye to eye, sparkling night sky and sky,
魔法の壁 どんなに痛くても全然減らない ああ 見つめたその瞳のラストはヤバイ
magic walls, no matter how much it hurts it never fades, oh, the climax of those eyes I gazed into is dangerous.
闇夜に星をサクッとハズナイン 虹色シューズで時間旅行 (1. 2.)
Plucking stars from the dark night, a time trip in rainbow shoes (1. 2.).
いたずら小悪魔はベイビーフェイス (oh yeah)
A mischievous little devil with a baby face (oh yeah).
なんだったっけレッスン (1. 2.) 冒険の気分 (oh yeah) ドキドキしたいわ (come on)
What was the lesson again? (1. 2.) Adventure mood (oh yeah) I want my heart to pound (come on).
指先にキラリ ネイルのブルーで (you're so hot)
With a sparkle on fingertips in blue nail polish (you're so hot).
paradise 空のカケラを閉じ込めたいな (二人だけでいたい)
Paradise, I want to lock away fragments of the sky (I want to be just the two of us).
見つめあうたびに おもちゃ箱を抜け出す
Every time we gaze at each other, we break out of the toy box.
(right now) 恋の (ah) メロディー (ah)
(Right now) catching the melody (ah) of love (ah),
つかまえて ! growing my dream (キミ 追いかけて into your dream)
growing my dream (chasing you into your dream).
テトテ メトメ ヒトリト ヒトリ 出会って 「ふたり」になる you & me (you & me)
Hand in hand, eye to eye, one by one, meeting to become "two" — you & me (you & me).
キミがいるって それだけで (sunny day ! rainy day !) “トクベツ” なの
Just having you there (sunny day! rainy day!) makes it "special".
オトガウタニ ココロガコエニ 出会って 言葉 に なる you & me (with the beat)
Sounds turn to songs, hearts to voices, meeting to become words — you & me (with the beat).
high より もっと full な ボリューム で 伝え たい baby love
I want to convey my baby love with a volume fuller than high.
1. 2. 3. 4. now, ready to the もっと 熱い ステージ へ
1, 2, 3, 4, now, ready to an even hotter stage!
ゲーム は ファンタジー だらけ、スタート から ゴール まで 愛 の ファンファーレ を 鳴らし...
Games are full of fantasy, ringing the fanfare of love from start to finish...
ヒトテ メトメ ヒトリ トヒトリ
Eye to eye, one by one,
出逢って ふたりになる
meeting and becoming two,
You & Me
いっそじゃないって それだけで
It's not just a dream, just that alone,
てまり てまり 始まりでしょ 夜が朝に 季節が鼻に
Temari, temari, it's the start, night turns to morning, seasons to flowers,
出逢って 未来になる
meeting and becoming the future,
You & Me
あいよりもっと ラブな笑顔で
With a smile more loving than love itself,
終わんない HAPPY DANCE
an endless HAPPY DANCE.
いっそおいでよ You & Me LET'S GO!
Come on over, You & Me, LET'S GO!
GO GO GO GO! レッツゴー
GO GO GO GO! Let's go,
You & Me GO GO GO GO!
まんざらファンキーピー GO GO GO GO!
Not bad, funky people, GO GO GO GO!
早立てろ皆の
Hurry up everyone's
It's only for you & me, だからチェックイラウト!
It's only for you & me, so check it out!
はーい、ということで！
Hi! So,
いやあ、今完璧なYou & Me見せちゃったんじゃないですか！
Man, didn't we just show you the ultimate You & Me?!
どうでしたか？ルナ、大丈夫？生きとるか？
How was it? Luna, you okay? Are you alive?
だいじょーぶ、だいじょーぶ……
I'm okay, I'm okay...
死んどるやないか！
You're practically dead!
いやあでも、力の限りを尽くしたこれがさ、
I mean, we gave it everything we had,
えらい！
Good job!
ねえ、なんでボタンじゃあ肩揉んでたの？
Hey, why was Botan massaging your shoulders?
いやなんかちょっと2番も頑張ってもらおうと思って
Well, you know, so she'd work hard on the second verse—
なるほどなるほど！
I see, I see!
頑張って、頑張ってねって
Saying 'do your best, do your best'!
そこテンションこの勢い強すぎてめちゃくちゃ叩いてたけどさ
With that much energy and hype, she was pounding you pretty hard though!
いやだってね、かけ声はもう気合いがすごかったから
Well, you know, the rallying cries had so much spirit in them—
気合いが！
So much spirit!
チョコ先生はもう全力でやってて
Choco-sensei was giving it 100%,
確かに！
True!
一人だけね、昇竜拳なんだよね。
And only one person was doing Shoryuken.
すげえな！
Amazing!
ねえ、というわけで皆さんありがとうございました！
Well, thank you everyone!
で、せっかくなので写真でもね、撮りたいなと思うんですけど
Since we're here, we wanted to take a group photo too,
写真撮りたい！
We want a photo!
じゃあルナたちも集合！
Luna and everyone, gather around!
やったー！
Yay!
じゃあちょっとね、目が、家族写真か。
Hold on, this looks like a family photo.
じゃあ撮るよー。
Alright, taking it.
このね、眼鏡もね、綿メカラサングラス借りました！イエーイ！ありがとうございます！パリピサングラスです！
We borrowed these wata-me sunglasses! Yay! Thank you! They're party people sunglasses!
はい、チーズ！
Say cheese!
ルナ、どこ見てんの？みんなどこ見てんの？
Luna, where are you looking? Where is everyone looking?
あ、はいはいはいはい！
Ah, yeah yeah yeah!
え、あとさ、ちょっとさ、チョコ先生とこのボタンちゃんが、あの足長いからさ、ちょっとこっち来て！
Oh, also, Choco-sensei and Botan have long legs, so come over here!
何々？スバルじゃできないことしてあげるわよ
What what? I'll do something Subaru can't do.
だってさ、足長いのうらやましいからさ、スバルを。ルナの足長いからさ。
Because I'm jealous of long legs! Luna's legs are long too.
ルナ長いでしょ、フェイククラブだろお前ら。
Luna's are long, right? You guys are a fake club.
だから足出してこうやって前に。足長いけどこうやって足出して。はい。
So stick your legs out in front. Even though our legs are long. Right.
足なげえ！ふたりとも！
Your legs are so long, both of you!
チョコ先生とね、私ね、腰の位置がおかしい！
Choco-sensei and me, our waist positions are ridiculous!
ちょっとこれやばいよ、ルナ。
Hold on, this is crazy, Luna.
やばい。なんかスバルたちやばい！
Crazy. Subaru and the others are in trouble!
え、じゃあさ、二人ともさ、ここでさ、こうやってさ、
Alright, so you two, right here, like this—
スバルたちゾンビしてるから、先輩っぽいの取りたくて。
Subaru and the others are doing a zombie pose, we wanted a senior-like one.
ここで、こうやってやって、二人で。
Right here, doing this together.
オッケー！
Okay!
すっ！おー！新感覚！
Swoop! Whoa! A new sensation!
ルナとスバルで、ここで背中合わせてにおわせ
Luna and Subaru backing up against each other—
チョコ先生、セクシーだ！
Choco-sensei is sexy!
やばい！まじでやばい！
This is bad! Seriously bad!
カメラの上の上に大御所感あるよ！
There's a big-shot vibe right above the camera!
あ、これですよ！
Ah, this is it!
あ、見下ろし視点になったらいい。
Ah, looking down on it is good.
あ、見下ろし視点ね。
Ah, looking down view.
あ、いいじゃんいいじゃん！
Ah, nice nice!
ちょっと、なんか椅子が、
Wait, somehow the chair—
椅子が気になる。
The chair is bothering me.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
これね、
This one,
ちょっと、サングラスも撮りたいな。
We want to take one with sunglasses too.
さ、さ、撮る？
Ready, ready, take it?
お、来た！
Oh, it's coming!
きゅん！きゅん！お、いいじゃん！しゃきーん！
Kyuru-kyuru! Oh, nice! Shakin'!
撮れたー！
Got it!
どこを向いても家族写真なんだけどさ、ありがとうございました。
No matter where we look, it's just a family photo. Thank you very much.
はい、ということでね。なんでこんな家族っぽくなっちゃうんだろう。
Right, so why does it end up looking so like a family?
ねえ、はい、ということでね。
Yeah, right, so,
今日はね、本当にね、来てくれてありがとうございました！
Today, thank you so much for coming!
いや、スバルもダンスの振ってとかありがとう！
And thanks for the dance prompts and everything, Subaru!
そう、ちょっとね、もうどれ、ど、どれが一番いいかなってね、朝まで考えたんでね。
Yeah, I thought until morning about which one was the absolute best.
ね、もう一回見直してくださいね、この後。
So make sure to review it again afterwards.
はい、じゃあ最後に、なんか、スバル3周年なのだから、「3周年おめでとう」って言ってバイバイしたい。
Alright, lastly, since it's Subaru's 3rd anniversary, I want to say 'Happy 3rd Anniversary' and wave goodbye.
オッケー、え、しゃあないな。
Okay, well, can't be helped.
しゃあないなあ、いいよー。
Can't be helped, sure.
なんかあれ、スバル変なこと言ったの？なんでこんなしんどくなっちゃうんだってなっちゃうんだ。
Did Subaru say something weird? Why did it get so tiring?
じゃあ最後みんな「おめでとう」って言ってくれる？
So everyone, can you say 'Congratulations' at the end?
はい！せーの！
Ready, go!
おめでとー！
Congratulations!
おっ、いいじゃん！
Oh, nice!
いや テンションの差が半端ない
Man, the difference in our energy is crazy.
せーのっ！
Ready, go!
え？ 何？ なんて言ったの？
Huh? What? What did you say?
温度足りてなかったろ！
Was our temperature not high enough?
じゃあせーのっで3周年おめでとうって言って？
Then let's say 'Happy 3rd Anniversary' on three, okay?
せーのっ！ ３周年！ おめでとう！
Ready, go! Happy 3rd anniversary!
おめでとう！ ありがとう～！
Congratulations! Thank you~!
ということで、一旦こちらこれで終了なんですわ！
With that, we'll wrap this part up for now!
みんなまたね！ ありがとうね！
See you all later! Thank you so much!
黒子だよ、黒子黒子……仲良しか！
We're stagehands, stagehands... As if we're close!
はい、というわけでですね、
Yes, and with that being said,
ここからまたどんどんダンスも踊っていきたいと思います！
from here on, we'll keep dancing more and more!
その前に一旦お着替えタイムに行きたいと思いますので、
Before that, we're going to take a quick costume change time,
みんなちょっと待っててね！ 行ってきまーす！
so everyone please wait a bit! I'll be right back!
お待たせしましたぁ！
Thanks for waiting!
ここからはもう後半戦に差し掛かっているので、
Now, we're heading into the second half,
後半戦だからってまだまだいけるよなぁ！盛り上がっていこう！
so let's keep the energy high and get even more hyped up!
それでは聞いてください、「夜もすがら君想ふ」
So please listen to 'Yoru mo Sugara Kimi Omou'.
僕が生まれる前よりも
Even long before I was born,
ずっと昔から続くように
continuing from way back in the past,
そういつも傷付け合って また愛し合うのさ
yes, always hurting and loving each other once again.
結婚や仕事のトークにまた ちょっと疲れてたとしても
Even if we get a little tired of talks about marriage and work,
そう僕も他人事なんじゃない 分かってるのさ
I know full well that I'm not unaffected either.
明けない夜はないと 夜明け前がただ暗いと
They say there's no night that doesn't end, and right before dawn is the darkest,
この先に待つ明日が そんなに輝くもんかなぁ
so I wonder if the tomorrow waiting ahead will really shine that bright.
今I Love Youではじまる僕らを もっと照らしてくれないか
Won't you illuminate us more, starting with an 'I Love You'?
変わらない愛や希望の類も まだ信じてみたいのさ
I still want to believe in things like unchanging love and hope.
ほらI Miss Youって諦めムードでも wow 飛び越えて行けるよ
Look, even in a give-up mood saying 'I Miss You', wow, we can leap right over it.
時代柄暗い話題が流行りだけど、愛を謳う
Even though gloomy topics are all the rage these days, I'll sing of love.
僕が取るに足らぬことで いつも悩んだりしてるのは
Always worrying over things of little consequence to me,
言っちゃえばアダムとイブから もう決まってたのさ
truth be told, was decided ever since Adam and Eve.
なんとなく恋に落ちて いつマ間にかに本気でって
Falling in love sort of naturally, before I knew it getting serious,
張り裂けそうな胸の奥を 打ち明けなくちゃな
I've got to open up the depths of my bursting chest.
今I Love Youではじまる僕らを もっと満たしてくれないか
Won't you fulfill us more, starting with an 'I Love You'?
イメージ通りには運ばぬ物としても 信じてみたいのさ
Even if things don't go according to plan, I still want to believe in it.
ほらI Miss Youって賞味期限がある Oh Yes 急かしてくれないか
Look, 'I Miss You' has an expiration date, Oh Yes, won't you rush me?
時代柄暗い未来が待ち受けど、愛を謳う
Even though a gloomy future awaits us in this era, I sing of love.
ああどうか夜明けまで 君の声が聴きたい oh yeah
Ah, please, until dawn, I want to hear your voice, oh yeah.
いつの時代も変わり映えなくってさ
In any era, without any change,
僕ら同じことで悩んだり 話したり
we worry about the same things or talk together,
笑ったりしてんのにさ 分かり合うのはそう簡単じゃない
or laugh, yet understanding each other isn't all that easy.
ただこんなにも君とリンクして 重なっていく
Yet we link with each other so much, overlapping more and more.
今I Love Youではじまる僕らを もっと照らしてくれないか
Won't you illuminate us more, starting with an 'I Love You'?
変わらない愛や希望の類も まだ信じてみたいのさ
I still want to believe in things like unchanging love and hope.
ほらI Miss Youって諦めムードでも wow 飛び越えて行けるよ
Look, even in a give-up mood saying 'I Miss You', wow, we can leap right over it.
時代柄暗い話題が流行りだけど、愛を謳う
Even though gloomy topics are all the rage these days, I'll sing of love.
ああどうか夜明けまで 君の声が聴きたい
Ah, please, until dawn, I want to hear your voice.
ずっと昔から続くように
As if it has continued since long ago,
そういつも傷付け合ってまた
yes, always hurting each other and
愛し合うのさ
loving each other once again.
結婚や仕事のトークにまた
Between talks of marriage and work, once again,
ちょっと疲れていたとしても
even if we were feeling a little tired,
そう僕も他人事なんかじゃない
yes, it's not like it's none of my business—
わかってるのさ
I know that well.
明けない夜はないと
There is no night that doesn't dawn,
夜明け前がただ暗いと
and that right before dawn is simply the darkest,
この先に待つ明日がそんなに輝くもんかな?
so I wonder if tomorrow waiting ahead will shine so brightly?
はーい！というわけで！
Hii! So anyway!
ふー！やば！このダンスに、もうちょっと待って、お水！
Whew! Wow! This dance—wait a second, water!
お水お水お水！
Water, water, water!
ふー、というわけでね！
Whew, so anyway!
夜もすがら君想ふはいかがでしたか？
How did you like "Yozumugara Kimisou"?
もう超難しかったんだよ、これ！
Man, it was super difficult, this one!
かっこよく踊れてたりしたでしょーか？
Do you think I looked cool dancing it?
ふっ、ということで！
Hmph, so!
それではここ、ここでですね、なんと！3周年記念グッズのご紹介をしたいと思います！
Now, here—right here, we have—is it time to introduce the 3rd anniversary merchandise!
どん！だだだだだーん！
Tada! Dun dun dun dun dun!
じゃんじゃんじゃん！
Ta-da!
はい、ということで3周年記念グッズですね！
Yes, so these are the 3rd anniversary goods!
まずフルセットがホワイトとブラックがあります！
First, the full set comes in White and Black!
これは何かと言うと、Tシャツの色が違うだけで、三周してください！
The only difference is the T-shirt color, please check it out!
特典もですね、
And the bonus is,
おじいちゃん描く！箱推し複製メッセージカード！
Grandpa's drawing! A box-oshi duplicated message card!
今回ちょっとね、あの時間がないんですけどね、カードがついてきます！
This time, well, we don't have much time, but a card is included!
しぐれうい先生の描き下ろしカードです！
It's a newly drawn card by Shigure Ui-sensei!
はい、そして内容はですね！
Yes, and the contents are:
えー、ラバーマット！ついに出るぞラバーマット！
Um, a rubber mat! A rubber mat is finally coming out!
ということでね、しぐれうい先生の描き下ろしのラバーマット、なんと！
So, a newly drawn rubber mat by Shigure Ui-sensei, and what's more!
メスまると！スバルが二人いるおじいちゃんスバル盛り合わせセット！
Mesumaru! Two Subarus! Grandpa Subaru's assortment set!
そして、えー
And, um—
ぷれ・あ・です！のですね、今回のライブタイトル「ぷれ・あ・です！」の、なんとCDが出ます！
"Ple-a-des!", the title of this live concert—a CD of "Ple-a-des!" is coming out!
なんだって！大体！
What?! Basically!
これはね、あの初のCDで、あのー、まあ、あのね、いろいろ入ってるんですよ、曲が。
This is, like, my first CD, and um, well, it has various songs on it.
ちょっと前が言えないんだけど。ちょっとあの曲が一般入ってて、あとカバーソングもね、あのカナリアと
I can't quite say beforehand, but... It has some general songs in it, and cover songs like "Canaria" and
あとファンサが入る予定です！あとオリジナルボイスもこの中につてます！CDよかったら買ってください！
"Fansa" are scheduled to be included! Also, original voice tracks are included in this! If you like CDs, please buy it!
え、そしてついにですね！Tシャツをね、出すことになりました！おめでとう！
And, um, finally! We decided to release T-shirts! Congratulations!
みんながねワンポイントが気やすいて言ったからね、ワンポイントのにしました！
Everyone said they wanted a one-point design, so I made it a one-point one!
これがホワイトとブラックがあって、え、セットもあるけどバラ売りもあるという感じです！
This comes in white and black, and you can buy them as a set or individually!
はい、そして
Yes, and—
え、なんと！なんと！新曲が出るぞ！
Um, what?! What?! A new song is coming out!
この新曲はですね、今回のライブタイトルの「ぷれ・あ・です！」という新曲が出ます！10月7日木曜日24時配信開始です！
This new song is titled "Ple-a-des!", the same as this live! It starts streaming on Thursday, October 7th at 24:00!
CDの中にもですね、「ぷれ・あ・です」入ってて、あとインストも入ってまっす！
The CD also includes "Ple-a-des", and the instrumental is in there too!
作詞はですね、Mitsuさん！
Lyrics by Mitsu-san!
そして作曲はですね、滝澤俊輔さんがしてくださいました！
And music composed by Shunsuke Takizawa-san!
マジで最強の曲なのでみんなぜひ聴いてください！はい！
It's seriously the ultimate song, so everyone please listen to it! Yes!
ということですね、ちょっと足早に駆けちゃって、汗がやばいんだけど（笑）無事にやった！
So, I rushed through a bit quickly, and my sweat is crazy (laughs). Successfully done!
はい、ということでですね、こっからですね、まだみんな聴きたい曲あるんじゃないの？
Yes, so from here on, don't you guys still have songs you want to hear?
あ、やごんなりポーズやっちゃった（笑）。聴きたい曲あるんじゃないの？
Ah, I did the Yago-nary pose (laughs). Don't you want to hear some songs?
なんとですね、今から「ぷれ・あ・です！」新曲をですね、披露したいと思います！
What's more, starting right now, I'd like to premiere the new song "Ple-a-des!"!
はい、もうラストなのでね！せっかくだからじゃあ真中のステージでね！
Yes, since it's already the last part! Since we're at it, let's go to the center stage!
踊って歌っちゃおうかな！
Let's dance and sing!
それじゃあ真中のステージに、レッツゴー！
So let's go to the center stage, let's go!
これね、長いんだよね！もうすごい！みんな見えてる？おー！
This is long, you know! It's amazing! Can everyone see me? Oh!
走っていくよ！
I'm running!
どん！
Go!
はあ、ということで、みんなね、ここからね、今からね、新曲歌って最後盛り上がってね終わりたいと思います！
Whew, so everyone, from here on, we're gonna sing the new song, get hyped at the end, and wrap it up!
新曲だけじゃないよ、まだ曲何曲かあるからね。はい、ということでね、最後まで盛り上がっていきましょう！
It's not just the new song, there are still a few more songs. Yes, so let's get hyped all the way to the end!
それじゃあ聴いてください！大空スバルオリジナルソング「ぷれ・あ・です！」！
Then please listen! Oozora Subaru's original song "Ple-a-des!"!
ぷ・れ・あ・で・す！
Ple-a-des!
ちょこっとヤンチャでニコっと元気な
A bit mischievous, with a grinning, cheerful
キラッとスマイル ア・イ・ド・ル！
sparkling smile—an idol!
毎日もっと楽しくしたい
I want to have even more fun every day
ドンヨク with アドベンチャー
Greedy with an adventure
ひらひらスカートも
Even my fluttering skirt
ちゃんと着こなせるんだよ
I can wear it properly
だからもっともっと好きになってもいいよ？
So is it okay if I make you like me even more?
一緒に大空に飛び立ったとき
When we flew together up into the open sky,
光れstarlight どんな輝きの中も
Shine, starlight, no matter how bright it is,
強いキラメキ
a strong sparkle,
キミに届いているかな？
is it reaching you?
1ミリでも伝われFight oh！
Even by 1 millimeter, transmit it, Fight oh!
チャージ！チャレンジ！全力アクセル
Charge! Challenge! Full throttle accelerator,
がんばる君へ
to you who are trying your best.
一番乗りスマイルを贈るスバルch
Delivering the first-place smile, Subaru ch.
everyday night & day みんなで！
Everyday, night & day, everyone!
ブルーな気持ちにズバッと駆けつけ お助けしちゃうヒーロー！
A hero who swoops in to rescue you from blue moods!
弱いハートじゃいられないから強強でいきましょう
Since we can't have weak hearts, let's go strong and steady.
ハラハラなミズギでドキドキのトキメキtime…？
With a fluttering swimsuit, a pounding, thrilling time...?
いつでもおいでよ一年中パラダイスとことん曇り空吹き飛ばそう
Come anytime, it's a year-round paradise, let's blow away the cloudy skies completely.
あがれ！スターマイン どんな闇の中も
Rise, starmine! No matter what darkness,
眩しく照らす
dazzlingly illuminating.
キミに見つけてもらえた
You found me,
それだけでもう運命なんだ
just that alone is already destiny.
もっとずーっと道は続いてく夢に向かって
The road continues on and on towards our dreams,
一緒に来てくれるかな？
will you come with me?
その手取って走れ
Take that hand and run,
つれていくよみんなで！
I'll take you along with everyone!
ささやかな言葉は恥ずかしいけれど
Modest words are a bit embarrassing,
こっそり、ね伝えたい想い
but secretly, you know, feelings I want to convey.
いまならいえるあのねドキドキ
Now I can say it, you know, my heart is racing.
キミのエールがチカラになるよ いつも元気分けてくれてがんばっていけるんだ笑って過ごせるんだ
Your cheers become my strength, always sharing your energy so I can do my best and spend days smiling.
ほんとにありがとうの気持ちを
The feeling of 'thank you so much',
歌え！starlight どんな輝きの中も
sing, starlight! No matter how bright,
強いキラメキ
a strong sparkle,
キミに届いているかな？
is it reaching you?
1ミリでも伝われFight oh！
Even by 1 millimeter, transmit it, Fight oh!
もっとずーっと道は続いてく夢に向かって
The road continues on and on towards our dreams,
一緒に来てくれるかな？
will you come with me?
その手取って走れ
Take that hand and run,
つれていくよみんなで！
I'll take you along with everyone!
キミとかけるスバル！
Running with you, Subaru!
想いの冒険を忘れずに全部言えるかな 君から聞きたいよ
Can I say all of our adventures in feelings without forgetting? I want to hear it from you.
何回目の僕に出会った？ 僕は変わりました
How many times have you met me? I have changed,
新しい君に出会うために 久しぶりだねって言えたならここで泣きそうか
in order to meet a new you. If I could say 'It's been a while,' I might cry right here.
好きとか嫌いとか 何度だって愛を歌う君が恋しくて 嘘じゃない本当だよ また出逢おう
Loving, hating—you singing of love over and over, I miss you. It's not a lie, it's the truth. Let's meet again.
思いの冒険を
Can I remember every bit
忘れずに全部言えるかな
of our adventure without forgetting?
君から聞きたいの
I want to hear it from you.
何回目の僕に出会った?
How many times have you met me?
僕は変わりました
I have changed,
新しい君に出会うために
so that I could meet the new you.
久しぶりだねって
If I could say "It's been a while,"
言えたならここで泣きそうか
I'd probably cry right here.
好きとかって
Saying you like me,
嫌いとかって
saying you hate me—
何回だって愛を歌う君が恋しくて
I miss you singing of love over and over.
嘘じゃない本当だよ
It's not a lie, it's true.
また出逢おう
Let's meet again.
僕ら“II”を嫌って“I”に戻って
Hating "II" and returning to "I",
何回だって間違ってきたよ
we've made mistakes so many times.
消えない後悔と 冷めない愛情が
Unfading regrets and an uncooling passion
恋を再起動する
reboot our love.
ほら“I”を嫌って また“II”に戻って
See, hating "I" and returning to "II",
“III”になって愛を繋いでいこう
let's become "III" and keep connecting our love!
言いたい感情は
The feelings I want to express,
伝えたい正解は
the right answers I want to convey—
想いの冒険は これからもちゃんと続いていく
our adventure of feelings will properly continue.
3と9に乗って 言葉とか飛び越えちゃって
Riding on 3 and 9, leaping right over words,
君も変わりました
you have also changed,
新しい誰かに会うために
so that you could meet someone new.
大人になりました
You've grown up.
それだけでいいと思えた
Just that made me feel it was enough.
好きとかって
Saying you like me,
嫌いとかって
saying you hate me—
何度だって愛を歌う君が恋しくて
I miss you singing of love over and over.
嘘じゃない本当だよ
It's not a lie, it's true.
また出逢おう
Let's meet again.
恋をして…バカ。
Fall in love... idiot.
愛にして…バカ。
Make it love... idiot.
バカでいい この先もずっとこのまま
Idiocy is fine, staying like this forever.
僕ら“II”を嫌って“I”に戻って
Hating "II" and returning to "I",
何回だって間違ってきたよ
we've made mistakes so many times.
消えない後悔と 冷めない愛情が
Unfading regrets and an uncooling passion
恋を再起動する
reboot our love.
ほら“I”を嫌って また“II”に戻って
See, hating "I" and returning to "II",
“III”になって愛を繋いでいこう
let's become "III" and keep connecting our love!
言いたい感情は
The feelings I want to express,
伝えたい正解は
the right answers I want to convey—
想いの冒険は これからもちゃんと続いていく
our adventure of feelings will properly continue.
メーデー
Mayday,
僕と分かっても
even if you realize it's me—
もう抱き締めなくて良くて容易いんだよ
you don't have to hold me anymore, it's easy.
終わらない愛を抱いていたいの
I want to hold onto an endless love.
もっとちゃんと不安にしてよ
Make me feel even more properly uneasy.
妄想感傷代償同盟
Delusion Sentiment Compensation Federation,
愛を懐いて理想を号泣
embracing love and crying out ideals,
行き場のある愛のメロディーを
giving a melody of love a place to go.
今まで本当にありがとう
Thank you so much for everything until now.
いつまでも君と
Forever with you,
「こんな歌あったね」って
so we can say, "Ah, that song existed,"
出会いを数えられるように
and count our encounters.